Research in human-vehicle interaction has shown even systems designed to automate driving are far from being error-proof.
人车交互领域的研究表明，即便是为实现驾驶自动化而设计的系统，也远非万无一失。
Recent evidence points to drivers’ limited understanding of what these systems can and cannot do as a contributing factor to system misuse.
近来的证据表明，驾驶员对这些系统能做什么、不能做什么了解有限，是导致系统误用的因素之一。
A recent study tackles the issue of over-trusting drivers and the resulting system misuse from a legal viewpoint.
最近的一项研究从法律角度探讨了驾驶员过度信任系统以及由此导致的系统误用问题。
It looks at what the manufacturers of self-driving cars should legally do to ensure that drivers understand how to use the vehicles appropriately.
该研究考察的是，自动驾驶汽车的制造商在法律上应当做些什么，以确保驾驶员懂得如何恰当地使用车辆。
One solution suggested in the study involves requiring buyers to sign end-user license agreements (EULAs), similar to the terms and conditions that require agreement when using new software products.
该研究提出的一种解决办法，是要求买家签署最终用户许可协议（EULA），这类协议类似于使用新软件产品时需要用户同意的条款和条件。
But this is far from ideal.
但这种办法远非理想。
The agreement may not provide enough information to the driver, leading to confusion about the nature of the requests for agreement and their implications.
协议可能无法向驾驶员提供足够的信息，导致驾驶员搞不清要求他们同意的究竟是什么、同意之后会带来什么影响。
Further, most end users don’t read EULAs.
此外，大多数最终用户并不阅读EULA。
A 2017 study shows 91 percent of people agree to them without reading.
2017年的一项研究显示，91%的人未经阅读就同意这类协议。
Among young people, 97 percent agree without reviewing the terms.
在年轻人中，97%的人不查看条款就表示同意。
The issue is that, unlike using a smartphone app, operating a car has serious safety risks, whether the driver is human or software.
问题在于，驾驶汽车不同于使用智能手机应用程序，无论驾驶者是人还是软件，都存在严重的安全风险。
And human drivers need to consent to take responsibility for the outcomes of the software and hardware.
而且，人类驾驶员需要同意为软件和硬件产生的结果承担责任。
“Warning fatigue” and distracted driving are also causes for concern.
“警告疲劳”和分心驾驶也是令人担忧的问题。
For example, a driver, annoyed after receiving continuous warnings, could decide to just ignore the message.
例如，驾驶员在接连不断地收到警告后心生厌烦，可能会决定干脆不理会提示信息。
Or, if the message is presented while the vehicle is in motion, it could represent a distraction.
或者，如果提示信息是在车辆行驶过程中显示的，它就可能让驾驶员分心。
Given these limitations and concerns, even if this mode of obtaining consent is to move forward, it likely won’t fully protect automakers from their legal liability should the system malfunction or an accident occur.
鉴于这些局限和担忧，即便这种征得同意的方式得以推行，万一系统发生故障或出现事故，它很可能也无法让汽车制造商完全免于承担法律责任。
Driver training for self-driving vehicles can help ensure that drivers fully understand system capabilities and limitations.
针对自动驾驶汽车的驾驶员培训，有助于确保驾驶员充分了解系统的能力和局限。
This needs to occur beyond the vehicle purchase.
这种培训需要在购车之后继续进行。
Recent evidence shows even relying on the information provided by the seller is not going to answer many questions.
近来的证据显示，即便依靠卖家提供的信息，也解答不了许多问题。
All of this considered, the road forward for self-driving cars is not going to be a smooth ride after all.
综合考虑这一切，自动驾驶汽车的前路终究不会一帆风顺。